Kellen Biondi

541.282.3817 | kellenbiondi@gmail.com | kellenbiondi.com/portfolio

Enthusiastic and artistic JavaScript engineer seeking a position in web applications. Knowledgeable on contemporary web libraries and frameworks. Capable in unit testing and using APIs. Experienced in business and finance, including coordinating projects with many inputs. Honest and skillful in working with others to achieve team goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- · Programming/Web: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node.js, jQuery, AngularJS, Express, REST, Github
- · Database: MongoDB, Microsoft Access, Hyperion Essbase
- Software: Microsoft Office (Excel / Word / PowerPoint / Outlook), Logic Pro, Ableton Live, MaxMSP,
 Pure Data
- · OS: Mac OS / Windows

PROJECTS

Project R - Open Source

2014

Project R uses the Instagram API to pull recent images by hashtag and create a slideshow for
projecting in public spaces. Responsible for creating the project's client side JavaScript. Worked with
a team to integrate with the design and server using Github for version control. The application uses
JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Backbone.js, jQuery, Cycle2, and Orchestrate.

Arduino Looper Pedal - Open Source (In development)

2014

 Currently working on building a guitar looper pedal using an Arduino Uno. The open source pedal is being designed to accept external midi signal and sync to the tempo so the artist can punch in/out and overdub exactly on beat.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Boeing Company - Financial analyst

2008 - 2013

 Developed quarterly forecast of roughly \$100M in annual cost. Maintained risks and opportunities, tracking financial impact and likelihood. Created ad-hoc reporting to identify trends and explain variances. Performed reconciliations and root cause analysis to ensure forecast quality.

Go Wireless - Salesperson

2007 - 2008

 Consistently met sales targets for activations, accessories, and gross profit. Provided information and services to customers. Discussed individual needs to recommend the best plans and phones.
 Maintained relationships by assisting customers with devices and insurance claims.

EDUCATION

Portland Code School

2014

Full-Stack Javascript

Southern Oregon University

2004 - 2008

- · Bachelor of Science, Business Administration Economics
- · Certificate in Applied Finance and Economics